Xavier University Library records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Library records
1903-2008
1925-2006
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Library.
7.5 linear feet (15 boxes)
These are records originating in large part from the Library Director's Office of Xavier University Library. Various documents are included including annual reports, correspondence, memos, meeting minutes, historical materials, budgeting and statistical materials, and other topical records.
XUA- 27
Scope and Content
This collection is a grouping of records stemming from the activities of the Xavier University Library. The collection includes both formal documents (e.g. annual reports, meeting minutes, etc.) and ancillary materials (e.g. budget preparation materials), all of which reflect the library environment for particular time periods. Some periods are not well documented in this collection.
Statement of Arrangement
Series I. Historical Materials, 1926-2003 Series II. Communications, 1903-2006 Subseries 1. Correspondence, 1925-1930,1946-1947,1968-1995 Subseries 2. Annual Reports, 1903-2004, bulk 1978-2004 Subseries 3. Library Director Memos, 1971-1999, 2006. bulk 1992-1999 Subseries 4. Meeting Minutes, 1977-2004, bulk 1992-1998 Subseries 5. Newsletters, 1980-2006 Series III. Planning Documents, 1975-2006, bulk 1994-2006 Series IV. Financial Information, 1979-2004, bulk 1992-2004 Series V. Statistical Information, 1970-2003 Series VI. Staffing Information, 1964-2006 Series VII. Activities and Services, 1975-2008 Series VIII. Policies and Procedures, 1969-2005 Series IX. Surveys, Reports and Proposals, 1976-2008 Series X. Consortia, 1993-2006 Series XI. Special Collections, Art, Gifts/Donors, 1932-2006 Series XII. Various Library-Related Issues, 1977-2006
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University archives staff.
Acquisition Information
This collection of documents was formed from various transfers of Library Director office files to the archives. In addition, other library-related historical materials already found in the archives was included to form the collection.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Libraries; Academic Libraries--Ohio
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Library Director
Detailed Description of The Collection
- I. Historical Materials, 1926-2003
  - Brennan Memorial Library (Edgecliff), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Library History Exhibit Signs, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Library History Items, 1926-2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lodge Learning Lab, 1984-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - McDonald Foundation, 1965,1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - McDonald Library Construction, approximately 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - McDonald Library Architect Correspondence, etc., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - McDonald Library Planning, 1962-1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - McDonald Memorial Library Furnishing Planning, 1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Library Planning Notes O'Callaghan, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - McDonald Library Library Building Committee Minutes, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - McDonald Library Dedication Planning, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - McDonald Library Dedication Program and Invitations, Address, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - McDonald Library Dedication Guest Book, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - McDonald Library Dedication Master of Ceremonies Program Notes, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - McDonald Library Congratulation Messages, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - McDonald Library Dedication Newspaper Clippings, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - McDonald Library Pioneer 68 Article, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - McDonald Library Dedication Cincinnati Enquirer Supplement, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Milford Library, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Schmidt Library Information and Correspondence, 1946-1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- II. Communications, 1903-2006
  - 1. Correspondence, 1925-1995, bulk 1968-1995
    - Correspondence of Library Director or about Library, 1925-1930; 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence of Library Director or About Library, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence of Library Director or About Library, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence of Library Director or About Library, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence of Library Director or About Library, 1988-1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 2. Annual Reports, 1903-2004, bulk 1978-2004
    - Annual Reports 1903;1934-1935, 1928-1935 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Annual Reports 1935/1936-1955/1956, 1936-1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Annual Reports 1965-1971, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Annual Reports 1979-1980, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Annual Reports 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Annual Reports 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Annual Reports 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Annual Reports 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Annual Reports 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Annual Reports 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Annual Reports 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Annual Reports 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Annual Reports 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Annual Reports 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 3. Library Director Memos, 1971-1999, 2006, bulk 1992-1999
    - Library Director Memos, 1971-1999; 2006 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 4. Meeting Minutes, 1977-2004, bulk 1992-1998
    - Library Professional Staff Meeting Minutes and Agenda, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Library Professional Staff Meeting Minutes and Agenda, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Library Professional Staff Meeting Minutes and Agenda, 1997-1999 March (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Library Professional Staff Meeting Minutes and Agenda, 1999 April-2002 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Library In-House Committees Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1977-2004 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 5. Newsletters, 1980-2006
    - Library Newsletters, 1980-2006 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - GCLC Hotline and Directories (Includes Xavier-Related Information), 1991-1999; undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- III. Planning Documents, 1975-2006, bulk 1994-2006
  - Academic Program Review: Psychology and Education, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Academic Program Review (Library) Library Reviews, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Academic Program Review (Library) Xavier Departments and Offices Responses, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Distance Education Library Services, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Environmental Scan, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Library Business Continuity Plan Draft, 2006 February (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Five Year Plans: ACRL, Staff Development, Library, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Library Goals 1977, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Library Goals 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Library Goals 1998-1999, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Library Goals 1999-2000, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Library Goals 2000-2001, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Library Goals 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Library Goals 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Library Goals 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Library Goals 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Library Goals 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Planning Day 1996 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- IV. Financial Information, 1979-2004, bulk 1992-2004
  - Library Budget Preparation 1980-1981, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Library Budget Preparation 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Library Budget Preparation 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Library Budget Preparation 1994-1995, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Library Budget Preparation 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Library Budget Preparation 1995-1996, 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Library Budget Preparation 1995-1996, 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Library Budget Preparation 1997-1998, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Library Baseline Adjustment 1998-1999, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Library Budget Preparation 1999-2000, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Library Budget Review 1994-1998, 1994-1999 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Library Budget Preparation 2000-2001, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Library Budget Preparation 2001-2002, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Library Budget Preparation 2002-2003, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Library Budget Preparation 2003-2004, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Library Budget Preparation 2004-2005, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- V. Statistical Information, 1970-2003
  - Statistical Information 1970-1983, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Statistics 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Statistics 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Statistics 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Statistics 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Statistics 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Statistics 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - North Central Accreditation Library Databook 1998, 1987-1998 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Library General Program Financial Data 1989-2003 Timeseries (Box 8, Folder 9)
- VI. Staffing Information, 1964-2006
  - Consult Four, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Library Organization Charts and Studies, 1964-2006 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Library Staff Reorganization, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Library Workforce Assessment, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- VII. Activities and Services, 1975-2008
  - Activities 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Activities 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Activities 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Activities 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 7b)
  - Activities 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Barcode Project 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Orientation to Library Services 1994, 1992-1994 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Orientation to Library Services 1996, 1994-1996 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Orientation to Library Services 1999, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Information Fluency, 2000-2007 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Information Fluency Institute, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Information Literacy In-Service, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Library Exhibits, Etc., 1991-2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Library Hours Bookmarks, 1990-2004; Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Library User's Guides, 1975-2008; Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Library Hours Bookmarks, 1990-2004; Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Library Instruction Materials, 1982-2002 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Literacy Center, 1993-1995 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - New Faculty Orientation, 2004-2007 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Periodical De-accession / Disposition Projects (Schmidt Library Stacks), 1989-1996 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- VIII. Policies and Procedures, 1969-2005
  - Policies (Collection Development), 1987-1996 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Policies (Various), 1996-2005 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Policies (Various), 1969-1998; undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Office Procedures Manual Audiovisual 1992, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Office Procedures Manual Circulation 2000;2001 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Office Procedures Manual Periodicals, 1994-1998 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Emergency Procedures Handbook, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Emergency Response Planning Communications, 1996-1999; undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Health and Safety Logbook, 2001-2002 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Response Procedures, 2004 October (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Safety Manual: First Response, 2005 October (Box 11, Folder 6)
- IX. Surveys, Reports and Proposals, 1976-2008
  - Burtchaell Consultation Report, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Library Studies and Reports, 1976-2000 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Library Surveys, 1977-2002 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Proposals: Ameritech Grant Promoting Information Literacy, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Proposals: College Resources Library Program, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Proposals: Family Literacy Education at Xavier, 1993-2002 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Proposals: LSTA Grant Proposal,1998 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Proposals: NEH Preservation and Access Grant, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Proposals: National Group, 2006, 2004-2005 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Space Utilization Study, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Study of Campus Life, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Vision Documents: Division and Library, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Vision Statement, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- X. Consortia, 1993-2006
  - AJCU Conference of Library Deans Bylaws, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - AJCU Historical Information: Benchmark Studies, Affinity Group, 1997-2006 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - AJCU Interlibrary Loan Information, 1993-2006 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - AJCU Meetings, Workshops, and Conferences, 1999-2004 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - AJCU Printing Survey, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - OhioLink, Ohio Library Network and Other Consortium Information, 1993-2006 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- XI. Special Collections, Art, Gifts/Donors, 1932-2006
  - Special Collections Various Items, 1946-2002; undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Special Collections Friel Collection, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Special Collections Kyte Bibles, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Special Collections Kyte / Williams Bibles, 1932-1965 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Art in the Library/ Special Collections Campus Art, 1963-2006 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Art:: Camele Campus Crosses, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Art: Doll Exhibit Vision Quest, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Art: Flecky Exhibit Hopkins, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Art: Trauth Dance of Tears Sculpture, 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Art: Weiss Exhibit, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Gifts and Donors Booklovers Association, 1971-2003 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Gifts and Donors Brueggeman Library Endowment, 1979-1983 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Gifts and Donors "B" Donor(s), 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Gifts and Donors "C" Donor(s), 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Gifts and Donors "K" Donor(s), 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Gifts and Donors Library Development Fund, 1992-1997 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Gifts and Donors "L" Donor(s), 1997 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Gifts and Donors "M" Donor(s), 1967 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Gifts and Donors "M" Donor(s), 2001 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Gifts and Donors "S" Donor(s), 1980-2000 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Gifts and Donors Small and Miscellaneous, 1972-1974; undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
- XII. Various Library-Related Issues, 1977-2006
  - Building Program Information, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Building Program Statement, 2003 December 10 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Copyright: Workshop, Policies, Correspondence, Printed Materials, 1999-2002 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Copyright Committee Xavier Library, 2001-2008 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - E-Audio Books, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Electronic Theses and Dissertations, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Faxon Bankruptcy, 2004-2006 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Flood, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Librarian Status 1977 and 1978 Proposals, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Librarian Status, 1987-1992 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Librarian Status, 1988-1992 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Librarian Status Faculty Assembly, 1999 March 12 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Building Prototype Planning, 2006 October (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Building McDonald Library Expansion Architectural Plan, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Technology Issues, 1978-2005; undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Innnovative Contract, 1989-1992 (Box 15, Folder 9)